- 嗨，大家 - 嗨！
- Hey,guys. - Hey.
亲爱的，这周末我有订到那个伍德福饭店
Honey,I got us that room at the Woodford Inn this weekend.
就是在佛蒙特的? 我的暗示果然有用!!
That place in Vermont? You can take a hint.
你们这周未不能外出啊 那天是艾玛生日
You can't go away this weekend. It's Emma's birthday.
会有一个派对
We're having a party.
能不能等我们回来再举办呢?
Can't you have the party when we get back?
那就会很怪，等于不是她真正的生日
No. It won't be her real birthday.
喔，更何况她才一岁 也不知道生日到底是什么
Gee,if only she were 1 and had no idea what the hell a birthday was.
嘿，这对我们很重要呢
Come on,you guys,this is really important to us.
喔，很抱歉，我和钱德 希望一起度过假日
Sorry,but Chandler and I could really use a weekend away..
- 我们想沟通沟通，心理上的 - 我们从以前就很想做这件事
- you know,to reconnect,emotionally. - There's this thing I really want us to do.
我在美信杂志看到的
I read about it in Maxim.
你们可以选择其他日子吧?
Well,can't you just go to Vermont the next day?
我们非常希望大家都能来...
Yeah,we want everyone to be there.
跟我非常讨厌你对我妹做 那奇怪的“性”事，一样多
As much as I hate to delay your doing weird sex stuff to my little sister.
这是一件大事呢
And,I mean,you know,you guys,this is a big deal.
她不能度过她的一岁生日 如果没有她姑姑和姑父陪她
How can we have her first birthday party without her aunt and her uncle?
我保证我绝对不会表演魔术的
I promise I won't do any magic.
好的，我们会留下来 还是可以赶过去
All right,we'll stay. We can just drive up after the party.
如果派对的事情害我们没做杂志上的事情…
Fine. But if we end up not doing this Maxim thing because of this party..
那不是理由，好不好?
Believe me,that is not why we won't be doing that.
艾玛的生日蛋糕
The.One.With.The.Cake
你知道吗，菲比 小的时候... 在我的生日...
You know,Phoebe,when I was little,on my birthday..
我爸会在家里每个房间藏礼物
my daddy would hide a present in every room of the house.
然后会给我们“宝藏地图” 叫我们自己找
And then he would draw a treasure map to help me find them all.
喔，我喜欢这种家庭习俗
I love family traditions like that.
但小时候，在我生日 我继父...
When Ursula and I were kids,on our birthday..
...会去卖他的血 来买吃的
our stepdad would sell his blood to buy us food.
- 嗨，大家 - 嗨
- Hey,guys. - Hi.
- 我带了摄像机，来录艾玛的派对 - 喔，好呢
- I brought the camera for Emma's video. - Oh,good!
我们想要录艾玛的派对
We had this idea to make a birthday video for Emma..
- 当她十八岁时，再拿给她看 - 喔，酷
- and we'll give it to her when she's 18. - Oh,cool.
- 就像一个“时空胶囊” - 是啊
- Wow,it's like a time capsule. - Yeah.
想象一下，到时
Oh,just think,she's gonna be watching that video on a TV..
她就会在一种现在还未发明的电视来看这个影带
that hasn't even been invented yet..
和朋友，当前跟她一样还是个婴儿，一起看
with friends who,right now,are just,like,babies.
然后，我们住在一个浮起来的城市...
And they'll be living in a floating city that the humans built..
...为了逃避蚂蚁人
to escape the ant people.
希望是如此!!
That's the hope.
- 所以，艾玛起来了吗? - 没有，现在午睡时间
- So is Emma awake yet? - No,it's still naptime.
- 不过，马上她就会醒了 - 乔伊在哪里呢?
- But she'll be up soon. - Where's Joey?
我说过了，现在是午睡时间
I said,it's still naptime.
- 嗨，来看看乔伊叔叔吧 - 嘿！
- Hey,there's Uncle Joey. - Hey.
说句话，给十八岁生日的艾玛吧
Hey,say something to Emma on her 18th birthday.
- 十八岁，哈? - 嘿，乔伊，不要…
- Eighteen,huh? - Joey,no!
怎么啦，怎么啦 ? 是要给艾玛很辣的朋友
What? What? It's for her hot friends.
当她看到这个，你已经是五十二岁了
When they see this,you'll be 52.
就是我开始稳定下来的时候呢
And starting to think about settling down.
乔伊，可以帮我打开吗? 这样就可以放艾玛的礼物
Joey,will you please set this up for people to put Emma's presents on?
喔，非常愿意呢
Love to. Yeah.
- 我们要给她礼物吗? - 是啊。我写了一首歌给艾玛
- We were supposed to bring presents? - Yeah. I wrote Emma a song.
我怎么知道？
Oh,yeah. How was I supposed to know?
- 这是一个生日派对呢 -是啊，但她仅一岁而已
- Joey,it's a birthday party. - Yeah,but for a 1-year-old.
重点在哪里? 那天她对着杯子大笑一个多小时
What's the point? The other day she laughed for an hour at a cup.
只是一个普通杯子 上面有艾魔（芝麻街的卡通形象）的农夫图案
Just a cup with a picture of Elmo on it,dressed as a farmer.
艾魔站在牛旁边 牛说了：艾-魔
And he's standing next to this cow,and the cow says,"El-moo."
真是好笑的杯子
Man,that's a funny cup.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
- 生日的女主角呢? - 她还在睡觉呢
- Where's the birthday girl? - Oh,she's still napping.
喔，当然，她昨晚知道要办一个派对... ...就太兴奋了，睡不着
She was probably up all night excited about the party she knows is happening.
我知道，你们很想去佛蒙特 对你们也是一件大事
I know you guys really want to get to Vermont,and this isn't a big deal to you.
但这对我们也是一件大事，好吗? 艾玛不会再有第二次的一岁生日
But it really is to us,okay? Emma will never have a first birthday again.
好的，你对，我们很抱歉
You're right. We're sorry.
那把艾玛叫醒，开始派对吧!!
Let's wake up Emma and get the fun time started!
她昨晚没睡好所以我们不能叫醒她
She didn't sleep well last night,so we can't wake her.
你是不是在跟我 开玩笑啊，格林!!
Are you frigging kidding me,Greene?
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi! - Hey!
- 很高兴你来了 - 真不敢相信，艾玛已经一岁了
- I'm so glad you came. - I can't believe Emma's already 1.
我还记得你的一岁生日
I remember your first birthday.
罗斯很羡慕我们给你的一切
Ross was jealous of all the attention we were giving you.
他很用力的去拉他的蛋蛋
He pulled on his testicles so hard..
所以我们要带他去看急诊
we had to take him to the emergency room.
有些关于你爸爸的事情你还不知道
There's something you didn't know about your dad.
嗨，盖勒先生和太太 我帮你放下来吧
Hey,Mr. and Mrs. Geller. Let me help you with that.
- 谢谢 - 见到你们真好
- Thank you. - Oh,man,this is great,huh?
我们三个又聚在一起 你知道更有趣的事吗?
The three of us together again. You know what would be fun?
就当做这礼物是我们 三个人一起送给艾玛的，怎样?
If we gave this present to Emma from all of us.
你是哪一位啊?
Which one are you?
- 真不敢相信，艾玛还在睡 - 我知道，但没辙儿啊
- I can't believe Emma's still asleep. - I know. What are we gonna do?
我有计划，一个好计划
I've got a plan. I've got a plan.
我会把这个铁盘 很用力的砸到你身上
I'm going to ram this platter really hard into your ribs.
那你会痛的哇哇大叫 这样会吵醒她，对不对?
You're gonna scream out,and that'll wake her up.
我不会和这种莫妮卡去佛蒙特的
I'm not going to Vermont with this Monica.
嗨，菲比，你知道吗?
Hey,Phoebe? You know what?
即然你写了歌给艾玛
I was thinking since you wrote a song..
那我也可以给艾玛表演我的才艺
maybe I could do something for Emma using my talents.
所以，你要去泡艾玛，是不是?
So you're gonna hit on her?
不是，不是啦 我的才艺是演戏
No,no,no. My talents as an actor.
我可能，可以…
You know,I could,like,maybe..
给她边读本书边演出来
I could do a dramatic reading of one of her books.
或是，你可以把一个叉子叉在苹果上?
Or you could stick a fork in an apple.
- 嘿，我想艾玛会喜欢呢! -喔，艾玛会喜欢什么?
- Hey,I think Emma might like it. - Oh,Emma might like what?
- 我的礼物! -你要给她什么?
- My present. - What did you get her?
- 实际上，我们正准备一个表演 - 分开的表演
- We prepared performances. - Separate performances.
但是差不多
But equally real.
喔，听起来好好玩
That sounds like fun.
你知道吗？因为大家 有点不耐烦要等艾玛起来...
People are getting a little antsy waiting for Emma to wake up from her nap.
...所以，你们可以现在表演一个吗?
So would you mind performing them once now?
- 当然可以 - 好…好，那好吧
- Sure,yeah! - Okay.
大家听着，我们开始吧
Okay. All right. Everybody,let's get this party started.
乔伊和菲比要表演给大家看呢
Joey and Phoebe are gonna perform a little something for us.
喔，太好了
Oh,great.
还没准备就上去表演，那你会不会觉的丢脸呢?
Aren't you gonna be embarrassed having nothing prepared?
嘿，我每个礼拜都这样呢，还加上 三个摄像机和所有团队等着我
I do it every week with three cameras pointed at me and a whole crew waiting.
那，乔伊，你要表演什么呢?
So,Joey,what are you gonna do for us?
我会边读艾玛的书边演出来
I will be doing a dramatic reading of one of Emma's books.
哇，好耶，哪一本?
Oh,okay. Which one?
哇，她最喜欢的其中一本
Well,it's one of her favorites.
从暴风雨中脱险： 对抗产后的抑郁症 咿…咿…咿
"Riding the Storm Out: Coping With Postpartum Depression."
始终爱你
Love You Forever.
始终爱你，作者：罗柏曼 萤火虫出版社出版
"Love You Forever,by Robert Munsch. Published by Firefly Books. Printed..
在墨西哥印刷
in Mexico.
一个母亲抱起她的婴儿 慢慢的，往前摇，往后摇
A mother held her new baby and very slowly rocked him..
往前摇，往后摇... 往前摇，往后摇...
back and forth,back and forth,back and forth.
当母亲抱着时，她唱了： 我会始终爱你
And while she held him,she sang,'I'll love you forever.
我会一直喜欢你 只要我还活着
I'll like you for always. As long as I'm living..
你就是我的孩子
my baby you'll be.'"
当母亲抱着时，她唱了：
"And while he rocked her,he sang:
我会始终爱你，我会一直喜欢你
'I'll love you forever. I'll like you for always.
只要我还活着
As long as I'm living..
你就是我的孩子
my baby you'll be.'"
哇！
Oh,wow!
哇，真的太棒了
That was amazing.
真的非常感谢你的礼物
Thank you so much for that gift.
今天我心理没有这个准备
I was not ready for this today.
- 太棒了，太棒了 -喔，菲比，抱歉
- Amazing. Amazing. - Phoebe,I'm sorry.
- 菲比也要表演给大家看 - 没错，
- Phoebe has prepared something as well. - That's right.
我准备了一首歌给艾玛 直接从我心里到她的心里
I prepared a song for Emma,from my heart to hers.
没有比音乐更好的礼物了
For there's no greater gift than the gift of music.
“艾玛” “你的名字给我一个困境”
Emma Your name poses a dilemma
“和你名字押韵的少极了”
'Cause not much else rhymes with "Emma"
“也许仅有演员理查德・克里纳” “他是演蓝波的长官”
Maybe the actor Richard Crenna He played the commanding officer in Rambo
“生日快乐，艾玛”
Happy birthday,Emma
就这样?
Is that it?
不，当然不是，还有…
No,of course not.
其他的… 我也要读一本书给她
No,I've also,you know,prepared a reading.
性爱和单身母亲
"Sex and the Single Mother."
- 查找性感带的方法 - 不要啊
- "Finding your G-spot." - Oh,no,no,no!
嗨艾玛,祝你十八岁生日快乐
Hello,Emma. Happy 18th birthday.
如果从现在算起，还有十七年之久呢
Right now,that seems so far away,17 years.
到时候你已经长大了，而到时候我们…-
Yes. You'll be all grown up by then,and we'll be..
你爷爷和我都不在了
Well,your grandfather and I might not be here.
没错，这信息
That's true. This message
会是来自我们的坟墓里
could be coming to you..from beyond the grave,Emma.
- 还有，我父母亲很年轻就过世了 - 我的胆固醇还过高呢
- After all,my parents died very young. - And my cholesterol's off the charts.
艾玛，请记得 女生也会因心脏病而死
Remember,Emma,heart disease kills women too.
好了，好了，这样就够了
Okay,cut! Great. Great. That was just..
- 噢！ - 哦，好的！
- Yeah. - Oh,good.
罗斯，别忘了要拍蛋糕
Ross,don't forget to get a shot of Emma's cake.
- 在盒子，在冰箱里 - 好的，没问题
- It's in a box in the fridge. - Okay,sure.
喔，你会喜欢这蛋糕 我从新泽西州的面包店买来的，加理诺面包店
You're gonna love this cake. I got it from a bakery in New Jersey,Carino's.
喔，他们有全世界最好吃的奶油
Oh,my God,that place has the creamiest frosting!
我小时候喜欢搭便车去那里
I used to hitchhike there when I was a kid.
无论如何，他们做了很多种口味
Well,anyway,they make these great novelty cakes..
很多种造型，如果你自己准备照片 他们还会放到蛋糕上
in all different shapes. And if you give them a photo,they'll copy it in icing.
-那你一定放艾玛的照片喽 -当然，在一个兔子形的蛋糕上
- Did you do a picture of Emma? - Yes. On a cake shaped like a bunny.
瑞秋，这家店是不是刚好
Rach? Does this bakery by any chance also bake..
也卖色情蛋糕?
erotic cakes?
上面写：给单身派对使用
Say,for bachelorette parties?
你在讲什么啊? 喔，我的天啊。
Ross,what are you talking..? Oh,my God!
他们还把 我女儿的脸放在“小弟弟”上
They put my baby's face on a penis!
这才像派对嘛
Now it's a party!
喔，如果真有那么好笑的话
Wait,you guys,this isn't funny.
我也可以自己做这种形状的啊
If I wanted this cake to be a disaster,I would have baked it myself!
啊，没事，我还是认为很好吃
Is it okay that I still think it looks delicious?
-杰克，你看看 -我知道你在想什么
- Jack,look at this. - I know what you're thinking,Judy.
其相似程度非常惊人
The resemblance is uncanny.
我也差点再度拉我的蛋蛋
I am this close to tugging on my testicles again.
讽刺的是,那和美信杂志一样.
Ironically,that was the Maxim thing.
不是，不是，这不是我要订的
No,no,this is not what I ordered,okay?
我特地去新泽西州 只为了我女儿有完美的生日蛋糕
I went all the way to New Jersey so that I could have the perfect cake..
还有，我需要兔子蛋糕。现在!!
for my daughter's birthday. And I need a bunny cake right now!
如果要快点的话，我们可以从“小弟弟”上取出她的照片，
Ask them if it would be faster if we cut the baby's face off the penis..
再贴到兔子蛋糕上
so we could put it on the bunny.
好像不是很适当
That is a weird sentence.
我会把蛋糕换回去
Oh,believe you me,I am going to bring this cake back.
甚至我不想有这种蛋糕在我家 乔伊，不要碰
I don't even want it in my home. Don't touch it!
我很困扰!!!
I'm so confused!
是的，我还是要我女儿照片 但是在兔子形状的蛋糕上
Yes,I still want my daughter's picture,but on a bunny cake!
黄色蛋糕，有奶油和花生!!!
Yellow cake,chocolate frosting with nuts!
说实在的，这上面没有花生
To be fair,this one does have nuts.
嗨，莫妮卡，你真好啊，把车借给瑞秋
Mon,it was nice of you to loan Rachel your car..
-为了她可以换蛋糕 -因为她一直拉我头发
- so she could get the cake. - It was nice of her to pull my hair..
直到我给她钥匙
till I dropped the key.
你知道吗，即然闲着
Well,while we're waiting,you could tape your message to Emma..
就先录一段给艾玛的十八岁生日 好不好?
for her 18th birthday,huh? Okay?
嗨，艾玛，现在是 2020 年
Hi,Emma. It's the year 2020.
你还在享受你的睡眠吗?
Are you still enjoying your nap?
我们是莫妮卡姑姑和钱德姑父
We're Aunt Monica and Uncle Chandler,by the way.
你可能不认识我们
You may not recognize us..
因为我们已经十七年没有和你父母亲讲话了
because we haven't spoken to your parents in 17 years.
我们本来已结婚
We used to be married.
但我们搞砸了我们的一个周末，造成我们分开
But then we missed a weekend away together,and things kind of unraveled..
就是因为你!!!
because of you.
-生日快乐!! -谢谢. 又一个有趣的胡扯
- Happy birthday. - Thanks. Another good one.
我不能相信我竟然录了这些.
I can't believe I taped over my Big Brother audition for this.
罗斯,瑞秋答应过这时候可以结束了
Ross,Rachel promised it would be over by now.
我们如果要去佛蒙特现在该出发了
We seriously have to go if we want to get to Vermont.
-我问过了，最后班次在半小时后 -你知道吗，我有要按摩的客户
- The last train leaves in a half-hour. - And I have a massage client soon.
嘿，大家，忍耐一下
You guys,just,please,a little bit longer.
瑞秋随时会回来
I promise,Rachel will be back with the cake any minute.
莫妮卡，记得这间店的奶油味道吗?
Monica,remember the frosting,huh?
好，我再等五分钟
All right,five more minutes.
喂?
Hello?
发生什么事?
Oh,no,what happened?
好的，好的，你在哪里?
Okay,okay,where are you?
我会过去的
Okay,I'll be right there.
那是不是艾玛? 她起来了吗?
Was that Emma? Is she up?
瑞秋因超速被警察拦下来
Rachel got pulled over for speeding.
她忘了带驾照，我得送过去
She forgot her license. I have to bring it to her.
-如果你要走，那我也得走 -等一下，如果有人要走那就是我们
- If you're leaving,I'm definitely going. - Wait,if anybody gets to go,it's us!
是我们抱怨最久的
We've been complaining the longest!
等等，你们不能退出
No,wait,you guys. No,you can't leave.
蛋糕的事已让瑞秋很烦
Rachel already feels bad that the cake's messed up.
如果回来时发现大家不在 那她会怎么觉得?
How do you think she'll feel when she comes back and you're gone?
我不知道，你礼拜一再告诉我吧
I don't know. You'll tell us on Monday.
乔伊，你负责这里，要确认没有人退出
Joey,you're in charge,okay? You make sure nobody leaves.
了解
Got it!
嘿嘿嘿，你要去哪?
Hey! Where do you think you're going?
去洗手间啊
To the bathroom.
即然大家会待一段时间 请当做自己家里…
Well,the rest of you get comfortable,because we are gonna be here for a..
-等等，洗手间里有个窗户... -不要让他逃走
- Wait,there's a window in there. - No! He's not getting away that easy!
喂，你们干什么啊!! 快滚出去啊!!
What are you doing? Get the hell out of here!
那个“小弟弟”上没有艾玛的照片
Well,that one did not have Emma's face on it.
-是，当然没有 - 对。
- No,it did not. - No.
已经很晚了，我们真的要走了
Well,we'd better get going. It's late.
杰克不能在晚上开车了 他没法让车保持在车道上行驶
Jack can't drive at night anymore. He has trouble staying in his lane.
去年冬天，我开车经过教堂的草地 然后撞上马的食槽
Last winter I went up on a church lawn and drove right through a manger scene.
报纸误以为那是一个报仇计划
The papers thought it was a hate crime.
-无论如何，很高兴可以见到你们 -好的
- Anyway,it was lovely seeing you. - Okay.
-再见 -晚安
- Bye. Bye,dear. - Nighty-night.
-晚安 - 再见.
- Nighty-night. - Bye.
-乔伊，你怎么可以让他们退出? -嘿嘿
- How could you just let them leave? - Hey,hey,hey.
我不会和杰克过不去的 他是一个好人，会保卫国家的
I'm not gonna mess with Jack. He's a great man. He fought for our country.
他才没有呢，他装成贵格会教徒 才可以逃离朝鲜
No,he didn't. He pretended to be a Quaker to get out of Korea.
够了，他是最后一个退出的 我把门锁上了
Well,that's it. He's the last one to go. I'm locking you guys in.
你知道那个锁是 可以从里面打开的
You do know I can just turn them the other way around,right?
喔，我忘了你以前住过这里
Oh,I forgot you used to live here.
-喂 -乔伊，我是艾斯黛
- Hello? - Joey,it's Estelle.
-嗨，你好 -你今天的试镜如何?
- Hey. - So how'd your audition go today?
-什么试镜? -上礼拜我和你说过的啊?
- What audition? - The one I told you about last week.
什么？你根本没有说过任何试镜!
What? You never said anything about an audition.
那我从新开始，我刚接到你的试镜通知
Let me start over. I just got a call about an audition.
你现在去还来得及
I think you can still make it.
就在艾斯特戏院，还要自己带独白
It's down at the Astor Theater,and you need to have a monologue prepared.
独白? 我没有呢…
A monologue? I don't have a..
有了...
I got it.
那我要走了
So I'm gonna take off.
-什么？ - 不，等等，你不能退出
- What? - No,wait! You don't get to leave.
我有按摩客户等在我家门外呢
I've got a massage client waiting outside my door any minute.
我们已经付钱给一个 我们现在应该住在里面的房间
And we paid for a room that we're supposed to be in right now!
好好
Well,okay,now..
只要有一个人照顾艾玛就行了
only one of us has to stay with Emma.
是我发现的这一点所以我可以走了
Okay,and as the person who realized that,I get to go.
不行，不行
No,no,no. No. No.
那我们想一个较公平的 方法来决定谁要留下来
Let's figure out a fair way to decide who's staying.
喔，有了。
Oh,I got it.
大家选择一到十的数字
Okay,everyone pick a number from one to 10,all right?
谁选到最大的数字可以先走
Whoever gets the highest number gets to go first.
-好喔，我选“十” -那我选“九”
- Okay,10. - Okay,Monica picks 10. I call nine.
还有其他的吗?
Anyone else?
-大家来抽签吧?	 - 好。
- No,let's just draw straws. - Okay.
或是可以用硬币…
Or we could flip a coin and multiply the answer..
-拜托你，不要讲话了 - 好。.
- I'm begging you to stop. - Right.
这样好啦，我们从艾玛的 生日礼物选一个发条玩具
Okay,how about this? We got wind-up toys for Emma.
拿来赛跑 哪个跑最后的，就要留下来
We can make them race,and whoever comes in last stays.
好吧，就这样
Yeah,let's do that!
这好像和佛蒙特的事情比起来，好玩多了!
That sounds more fun than the thing we were gonna do in Vermont!
- 好，各位，开始选玩具吧。 -我要用那个海豚!!
- Okay,everybody,pick your toys! - Okay. I want the dolphin!
-菲比，那是一只熊 -抱歉，我太兴奋了!!
- That's a bear! - I'm too excited!
菲比，你用这只熊 乔伊，你用机器人
Phoebe,you get the bear. Joey,you get the robot.
-哦，好的。 -钱德就用这只狗吧
- Oh,yeah. - And Chandler and I get the dog.
比赛就要开始了... 从这里，到这里
And the race is going to go from here to here.
谁最后一名的，要留下来!!
Now,the one who comes in last stays!
各位先生及女士，卷好你的发条
Okay,ladies and gentlemen,wind your toys.
-准备了吗?预备，开始！ -快，快!!
- Okay. On your mark,get set,go! - Go! Go!
不要停!机器人！
Come on,robot!
你在干什么啊?!!?
What are you barking at?
那个动作有什么作用吗!?!?
Well,how is that gonna help?
我买了你! 我竟忘了你只会这个动作?
I bought you! How did I forget that that's all you do?
好样的,机器人!
Way to go,robot!
干的好，阿伦
Good job,Alan.
-真是一个好比赛 -是啊，那就再见喽
- Hey,good race,you guys. - Yeah,see you later.
不，不，你们等一下
No. No,no. Wait.
我们没有输呢
We didn't lose.
规定是说，最后跑到终点才是输家
The rules clearly stated that the last one to cross the finish line was the loser.
那我们的狗，没有跑到终点，所以技术上来说…
Well,our dog never crossed the finish line. So technically..
他们已经走了!
They left.
你知道吗? 根本没时间去面包店 所以我们现在回家了
There isn't time to go to the bakery. We're gonna come home.
大家已经走了?
Everybody left?
好吧，告诉艾玛我们会尽快回家，再见
All right. Well,just tell Emma that we'll be there as soon as we can. Bye.
-瑞秋!!! -喔，天啊，抱歉
- Rachel! - Oh,God,sorry!
真不敢相信，他们给了你一个罚单 你真是一个好驾驶人
I can't believe they gave you a ticket. You're such a good driver.
-艾玛起来了 -是喔?
- Emma's awake. - Yeah?
真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
在她的一岁生日 她醒来时，我们不在
This is her first birthday,she's awake,we're not even there.
大家也已经退出了 还加上这个烂蛋糕!!!
Everybody left. We still have this stupid obscene cake.
嘿，也许我可以弄好这蛋糕 试试看，改成别的形状嘛
Hey,maybe I can fix that. You know,try to turn it into something else.
已经无所谓了
Oh,don't even bother.
我们已经毁了她的第一个生日
We've already ruined her first birthday.
你不知道这些早期的经验对她有多重要吗，罗斯?非常重要
And do you know how important these early experiences are,Ross? Very!
依照你给我的那本书的背面图案弄
According to the back cover of that book that you gave me.
瑞秋，她不会记得这些
Rach,she's not gonna remember this.
也许吧
I guess.
喔，我本来想像今天是怎样的一天
Oh,I just had such an idea of what this day would be like,you know?
艾玛在笑
Emma laughing..
大家围绕著蛋糕唱“生日快乐”
and everybody gathered around her cake,singing "Happy Birthday."
然后…嘿，不要挡路你这个笨蛋新手!!!
And then we would all.. Hey,get out of the road,you stupid student driver!
他们总要学这点
They have to learn.
-嘿 -什么?
- Hey. - What?
这不错嘛
This is not bad.
喔，天啊。你怎么弄的，罗斯?
Oh,my God. Look,you made it into a bunny. How did you do that?
我把这边改成脸颊
Well,I just made these two things cheeks.
这部分再分两边，变成耳朵
And then I split this to make ears.
喔，我非常感动呢
Well,I am very impressed.
有些人会唱歌，有些人会跳舞
Some can sing,some can dance.
我显然的可以把“小弟弟”改成兔子蛋糕
I,apparently,can turn phallic cakes into woodland creatures.
还有另外一种方法来整理玩具 就是按照大小
Now,another way to organize your stuffed animals is by size.
对不起，这是给艾玛玩的游戏，或是给莫妮卡?
I'm sorry,is this a game for Emma or for Monica?
游戏?
Game?
你知道今天是你生日吗? 你是一…
Emma,do you even know it's your birthday today? You're 1.
就是一岁，这么小
One year old. That's little.
天呐我的女儿
That's my girl.
这就是你的年龄
That's how old you are.
是我教她的吗? 或是我传授智能给她?
Did I teach her that? Did I just impart wisdom?
喔，我也想要有一个
I want one.
我也是
Me too.
这里没人，干脆我们带走她，好吗?
There's no one around. Why don't we just take this one?
-然后跑去加拿大? -我在开玩笑
- And head to Canada. - I was kidding.
我可没有呢!! 快点出发吧
I wasn't. Let's get going.
-嘿，罗斯和瑞秋回来了吗? -还没有呢
- Hey,are Ross and Rachel back? - No,not yet.
-喔，好耶，我没错过派对嘛 -那你的按摩客户呢?
- Oh,good,I didn't miss the party. - What about your massage client?
我觉得很内疚如果错过这派对 所以我给了他一些东西
I just felt so bad missing this. So I just slipped him a little something,you know.
五或六个小时后再做也可以
As long as I'm back in five or six hours,it'll be all right.
好！
Okay.
嘿，如果罗斯、瑞秋问起我， 说我一直待在这里
If Ross and Rachel ask,I've been here the whole time. The whole time.
我一直待在这里的
I've been here the whole time.
乔伊，我们刚看到你进来 而且你跑上来时，在楼梯超过了我们
Joey,we just saw you come in. You ran past us on the stairs.
我不管你有没有退出 我很高兴你们现在在这里，谢谢大家
I don't care that you left. I'm just glad that you're here. Thanks,you guys.
嘿，大家过来 你们应该看看艾玛刚做了什么
Hey,guys,come on. You gotta see what Emma just did.
- 什么? -艾玛，你几岁?
- What? - Emma,how old are you?
你今天几岁?
How old are you today?
对了， 艾玛，你就是一岁
Emma,that's right. You're that many.
喔，天啊，我们女儿是一个天才
Oh,my God,our daughter's a genius.
-这表示… -不要有科学的说教了
- This means.. - No! No science camp!
喔，真是的，我把蜡烛放到蛋糕上
Damn it! I'll put a candle on the cake.
喔，艾玛，看看你的玩具排的如此整齐
Oh,and,Emma,look at your stuffed animals lined up so neatly.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了，要开始了
Okay,here we go.
这是艾玛第一个生日蛋糕
Emma's first birthday cake.
快吹啊，吹灭蜡烛
Go ahead,Emma,blow out the candle.
快，艾玛，你能做到的。
Come on,Emma. You can do it.
-怎么啦，你还好吧? -喔，没事
- What's wrong? Are you okay? - Oh,yeah,nothing.
这是快乐的眼泪
These are happy tears.
这就是我想要的
This is just what I wanted.
嘿，蛋糕已变成兔子形状了
Hey,you made it into a bunny.
喔，我怎么啦，为什么我觉得“小弟弟”的形状时看来比较好吃
What is wrong with me? It looked more delicious when it was a penis.
-好，准备好了吗? -是的
- Okay,you ready? - Yeah.
-那，开始录了 -好。
- And record. - Okay.
试音.
Big Brother audition. Take one.
我猜你会说 我是一个演员..
I guess you could say I'm kind of a player.
好了.让我...
Okay. Let's..
- 让我再试一次. - 好的.
- Let's just try that again. - Okay.
嗨，艾玛，你的生日刚结束了 而且…
Hi,Emma. Well,your first birthday is over,and..
快啊，快啊
Go! Go! Come on!
快啊，快点
阿伦，快跑啊 你这个毛绒绒的混蛋
Go! Go,Alan! Run,you hairy bastard!